This tastes terrible.
S-Sorry.
The only good that came out of this
was that I can now appreciate
the coffee my household staff brews.
This tastes like stewed sea slugs.
I'll ask Secretary Fujiwara
to show me how to brew coffee.
Fujiwara suddenly finds herself
in a tight spot.
Shinomiya's sure in a horrible mood.
Persona!
Every one of us plays a different role
for other people, depending on what they seek.
Who you are when you're with friends.
Who you are when you're with a lover.
Not to mention who you are online.
There! "L-O-L!"
All the more so if you're
a member of the Shinomiya Family.
The upbringing she received
was positively spartan...
so in order to shield her mind
from that environment,
she has been known to frequently
produce robust personas.
These masks, so deeply ingrained in her life,
can be so unyielding at times...
that you would think...
she was someone else entirely.
Shirogane...
I mean "President"...
Shall we discuss
what happened the other day?
Here it comes!
How would you define
our relationship, President?
Student council comrades...
doesn't sound at all inspiring.
Friends...
doesn't sound right, either.
Since we've come this far...
I'd say...
that we're boyfriend and girlfriend...
maybe.
Boyfriend and girlfriend
is a bit far-fetched, isn't it?
Seriously?
One kiss, and you're acting
like my boyfriend?
Only a child would believe
that a kiss makes you instant lovers.
Well, not that I blame you
for getting ahead of yourself, President.
After all, I've known from the start
that you had feelings for me.
Who are you to talk, Shinomiya?
What was your reason for kissing me?
You did it because you like me, right?
In that case...
I wish you wouldn't make
such a commotion over a mere kiss or two.
Please, I would kiss anyone
if I was in the mood.
On that note...
would you like to do it now?
Kiss?
What's this?
A man waiting for a kiss?
How creepy!
No, I was just... I thought...
I thought she was going to force
a kiss on me again!
That kiss is carved
deep inside Shirogane's mind.
Hey... I know it was kind of...
But you didn't have to hit me!
I apologize.
But it's the Shinomiya way
to discipline the indecisive by hitting them.
Anyway...
I don't see myself
wanting to date such a spineless man.
We're done for today. Good night.
Huh?
Oh my.
I was planning to call
for someone to pick me up...
but apparently,
smartphone batteries drain quickly.
Therefore, I shall walk home.
Huh? Are you sure you should be
walking home alone at this hour?
Then, what do you propose?
What's gotten into Shinomiya?
I thought things were pretty great
until yesterday,
but now she's saying
she doesn't want to date me.
And here she is, walking home with me.
And that cold look on her face... Like ice.
It's like she's reverted to being the Shinomiya
who rejected everyone around her!
Something happened! I just know it!
Did her father give her a hard time
about studying abroad?
Or maybe he's against her dating!
Don't tell me she's going to announce
that she has a fiancé!
Is that why she took this long
to tell me that she couldn't date me?
Figure it out, Miyuki!
Shinomiya's got to be sending
some kind of sign!
You men are certainly lucky.
Even if you walk around with your hands
in your pockets like that, no one reprimands you.
My fingertips feel frozen.
Shinomiya's sighing because
she's thinking about male privilege.
In the Shinomiya household,
where they treat people like objects,
one example of male privilege would be...
Could it be a fiancé after all?
Shirogane is quite agitated.
Shinomiya, what is it
that you want me to do?
Just tell me what you're feeling!
Really, it's so bitterly cold!
It feels like my heart
is about to get frozen, as well!
One of us seems to have
warm hands! How lucky!
Does that mean she wants me to rescue her
from the cold with my hands?
This is Shinomiya's cry for help!
I...
I have to do something about this!
President...
I see that you're not even capable
of escorting a girl home the proper way.
How cute.
So spineless.
L-O-L... I say.
You don't have to put my hair up today.
Oh my.
But is there still some of that perfume
my sister-in-law gave me?
Oh my, oh my.
84 sheep...
85 sheep...
86 sheep...
87 sheep...
88 sheep...
Sheep...
One coffin...
Coffin?
Two coffins...
Hey, what do you think
you're counting, President?
Three coffins...
What do you mean?
I'm counting sheep.
I didn't get any sleep last night.
No, you started counting coffins
midway through!
Please don't count anything that suggests
you won't wake up once you fall asleep!
Morning, two days before Christmas Eve.
There are now cracks in Shirogane's heart.
And no wonder.
Just when he thought he'd finally
get to start dating Kaguya,
thanks to the culture festival
and all its promise,
Kaguya suddenly... uttered the words,
"I cannot date such a spineless man!"
And as if that weren't enough...
How cute.
Trauma words!
You can't blame him
for suffering a mental collapse.
Maybe I'll go look at the penguins
in the aquarium.
Hello!
Hey...
You're wearing your hair straight, Shinomiya.
You haven't done that
since you put makeup on me.
Yes, I remember that day.
I have my makeup kit with me today,
so would you care to do it again?
Uh, no, I think I'll pass.
Well, what a pity.
Huh?
She's in a good mood today.
Morning, Shinomiya!
Huh?
Snub.
Why's she ignoring me?
About the Christmas party I'm throwing...
Yes?
First, a toast! Of course
it'll be with non-alcoholic drinks!
Listen, didn't you think
Shinomiya was acting weird today?
Yes, of course.
And we'll save the gift-exchanging until last!
No. She was the same as usual with me.
Sounds good to me.
And I thought we could all have hot pot
before we all get into a Christmas-y mood!
Sounds good to me.
And she's acting
like her usual self with Fujiwara.
If we're talking weird,
she was way weirder yesterday.
Yeah, that was a sight to see, too.
Pwesident! Pwesident! Pwesident!
I really need to talk to her again, properly.
Vice President Shinomiya...
You're wearing perfume, aren't you?
That's against the rules.
Oh my. It's only the slightest of dabs.
Your sense of smell is astounding.
No. Take this as a gift from me, Iino.
What?
Don't you ever use perfume?
Of course not. I never...
Oh? But Christmas
is just around the corner.
This is as good a time as any
for you to learn, is it not?
Your body, Iino...
smells so sweet.
Perfume is fragrant
because it blends with your body scent.
The nape of your neck is warm, so applying it
there will really bring out the aroma.
As long as you apply it 30 minutes
before seeing the person you wish to conquer...
your body temperature
will have done its job by then,
and you'll be able to draw
that gentleman toward you.
And now you're just as guilty.
But...
doesn't this smell like something
a middle-aged woman would wear?
Like someone who's really pushy.
I don't think it's for high school girls.
Wrong! As I explained earlier, a perfume's scent
changes with the passage of time.
Yes, it's an acquired taste initially,
but after 30 minutes—
Shinomiya...
Even right now,
it doesn't smell at all like—
Do you have a minute?
It smells just like my middle-aged aunts.
Shinomiya?
Why are you running away, Shinomiya?
Kaguya?
Shinomiya...
Why?
What did I do?
What did I ever do to you, Shinomiya?
You can't get away from me now!
Why did you run, Shinomiya?
Don't come near me! Please!
I'm telling you...
Don't come any closer to me!
She hates me that much?
Tell me...
why.
The answer is simple.
Because it hasn't been 30 minutes yet
since Kaguya applied the perfume!
With the passage of time,
perfume changes as follows.
The perfume Kaguya has on
is renowned for its middle note!
Immediately after applying it,
it smells somewhat old-lady-ish.
But...
at this very moment, it hits her!
Thanks to that dramatic chase, her body temp
has surged. And she's sweating profusely!
The middle note emerges
when the aroma evaporates,
blending with the wearer's own scent
in the most optimal way. Also known as...
"the heart note," which has now arrived!
Fine. From now on,
I'll keep my distance, Shinomiya.
Come back here.
What?
Where do you think you're going?
Huh?
But you just told me to get lost!
You can stay now.
Actually, you have to stay or else.
I have no clue about the female mind!
Hey, Shinomiya... Don't you think
you were acting strange yesterday?
I was the same as always.
The one thing that comes to mind...
is that perhaps I was suppressing
the absurd side of me that got a bit carried away.
Carried away?
Though I did make an outrageous
promise to study abroad,
once I regained my composure
and gave it some serious thought,
I realized that it was a decision
so horrific, it left me shaking.
Then, was that kiss also something you did
because you were carried away?
I suppose you could say that.
You seem to be taking
that kiss extremely seriously,
but for me, that's all
a kiss really amounts to.
On that note, would you like
to do it right now?
Kiss me?
Huh?
I could never do that!
A kiss isn't something
you do so casually!
If you're not feeling it,
there's just no point—
Ow! Why'd you kick me?
Pardon me.
It's the Shinomiya way to kick anyone
who'd hold a kiss more sacred than they should.
What the heck are you
so mad about? Just tell me!
Well...
You've been blowing me off,
you look more gloomy than usual,
you're letting your hair down,
you resort to violence!
And you smell so nice
like perfume, which you never use!
I'm worried about you, okay?
Did you say I smell nice?
Yeah, I did! You smell amazing!
And this has to be a first, right?
If only you'd noticed
like you did just now...
then I'd always be in a good mood.
I know this is a real stretch...
but last night, when you were going on and on
about how cold you were...
you weren't hinting that you wanted
to hold hands, were you?
And it's because I didn't hold your hand...
that you're mad.
Of...
- Of course that's not what this is about!
- Shinomiya!
Yeah, of course not.
Now you realize?
You want to consult me about love?
Yes. As someone with a boyfriend,
I thought that I could benefit
from hearing your opinions.
Well, of course I don't mind.
You're letting your hair down today, I see.
It reminds me of when we were first-years.
Back then, you...
were known as "Kaguya the Ice Princess."
So unapproachable... Everybody's idol...
Mine included...
Back then, she was attractive
in the same way as Maki during her tense moments.
So, Kaguya—
I've been wondering about this
for quite a while.
You frequently change the way
you address me, do you not?
You're the only one at this school
who's so informal with me.
In fact, you address me
as if we've always been close.
My apologies! That was
overly familiar of me, wasn't it?
No, I don't mind.
I'm sorry! I won't address you
so informally again, Miss Kaguya!
I really don't mind.
Are you serious, Miyuki?
You want my advice about love?
Yeah.
I'd really like to learn
more about how girls feel.
I see. So as long as she's a woman,
anyone will do.
Don't put it that way!
Well, if that's what you're after,
leave it to me.
After all, I'm a master of romance.
Huh?
I'm kidding.
You're kidding?
Never once have I experienced
a successful romance.
Look how blue the sky is.
Damn, I asked the wrong person.
So?
So...
what is it that you wanted to ask me?
President has absolutely no clue
about my feelings for him.
President has no clue about my feelings...
President has no clue—
Are we talking about you and Shirogane?
Yes, that's what I'm telling you.
But normally, you'd start by saying,
"I have this friend who..."
You're already well aware, aren't you?
Meaning that any such pretexts
would be a waste of time.
Realizing how ineffective it is
to use the friend ploy! So impressive!
Miss Kaguya,
you're 100 times smarter than usual!
Well, this is about a friend of mine, okay?
The woman actually said this.
That she'd kiss anyone if she was in the mood.
And then she asked,
"Would you like to do it now?"
I mean, who says that?
Actually, that sounds so sweet!
I know exactly how that girl feels!
So, she'd kiss anyone
as long as she was in the mood?
Obviously, she's trying to hide her true feelings
behind those assertive words.
True feelings?
What she's really saying is,
"You're the only one I'd ever be in the mood to kiss."
If you wanna dig even deeper,
what she's really trying to say is...
I want President to kiss me.
What am I supposed to do?
I tried every which way
to make President kiss me,
but so far, nothing's worked,
and I'm at the end of my tether.
You want President... to kiss you?
Yes.
Kiss you, Miss Kaguya?
That's exactly what I just said.
But why?
For someone who already knows,
that's quite a mean thing to ask.
Because I'm in love with President.
What other reason could there be?
Ka...
Kaguya!
Why are you back to addressing me
informally now?
But... I can't believe
you owned up to it just like that!
I've already acknowledged
my romantic feelings for him.
Romantic feelings?
If I'm in love with him,
isn't it only natural to want him to kiss me?
I want him to hold me close
with those arms,
and if he wants to go even further,
I'd probably say yes—
I got it! I got it, okay?
At any rate, if you want him to kiss you,
then all you have to do is be honest with him
about your feelings, right?
That, I cannot do.
Why not?
Whenever I'm in his presence...
for some reason,
I can't help being perverse.
I totally get it!
That's just it! Being with the person you love
makes you act all hostile and aloof!
Actually, does "hostile and aloof"
really explain that behavior?
I've been making all kinds of efforts!
Like repeating over and over how cold I was,
to get him to hold my hand!
I mean, she's walking right next to me,
venting all the while!
And today I even put on some perfume!
Then she ran off like her life depended on it!
The truth is, I'm too embarrassed
to even talk to him!
When I said hello, she ignored me!
The truth is, I'm too embarrassed
to even talk to him!
When I said hello, she ignored me!
The truth is, I'm too embarrassed
to even talk to him!
When I said hello, she ignored me!
The truth is, I'm too embarrassed
to even talk to him!
When I said hello, she ignored me!
The truth is, I'm too embarrassed
to even talk to him!
When I said hello, she ignored me!
The truth is, I'm too embarrassed
to even talk to him!
When I said hello, she ignored me!
Have some empathy!
I'm asking you myself! Please try to have
some empathy for how she feels!
She's almost at the breaking point herself!
So please, try to be understanding!
You know, this person
is the exact same type as me.
I'm feeling so much sympathy for her,
it's downright scary.
If you told me we were related,
I'd believe—
Wait.
Is this about you and Auntie Kaguya?
I've had a feeling about you two for ages!
How far have you gotten?
What? No, actually...
We shared a grown-up kiss
at the culture festival.
Whaaaaat?
I thought we were friends,
but you've beaten me to the punch!
I wish I hadn't found out!
A grown-up kiss!
About 40 seconds.
And now, the dots have been connected.
But... that kiss was a mistake.
Are you sure about that?
What was your first kiss like,
Miss Kashiwagi?
Huh? You're making this about me?
We were on our way home after a date.
And while we were waiting
for the light to change...
out of nowhere, he...
I wish I'd never found out!
That's quite lovely.
But it was all of a sudden
in front of a mini-mart!
There's nothing romantic about that.
That's fine.
I'd rather have an ordinary kiss
just like everyone else in this world.
All I want...
is an ordinary romance.
I wonder...
what Shinomiya...
thinks of me.
Ice Kaguya is one of Kaguya Shinomiya's
many diverse sides.
She is...
the manifestation of the wariness
everyone has toward one another.
At the same time, she is also
the cowardly heart of one who's in love.
But I love you.
Today's battle result...
Kaguya Shinomiya...
loses.
Miyuki's betrayed me!
You're the only one for me, Yu!
An unhinged person just threw herself into my
arms saying the weirdest things at the worst time!