This is a story only she and I know about.
The story of the secret of this world.
It was like a pool of light.
She ran out of the hospital.
Praying with all her heart,
she crossed the shrine gate.
Fish?
Now I wonder if what I saw
that day was just a dream.
But, it wasn't.
That summer day, up in the sky,
we changed the shape of the world.
We're expecting very heavy rain shortly.
It's gonna rain again.
I thought it had finally cleared.
We ran into a typhoon on the island too.
Excuse me.
Sorry.
For your safety, please go back inside.
Here it comes.
Wow!
Thank you.
What a storm it was.
This is delicious.
Sure you don't want any?
Yeah. I'm not hungry.
Really? Thanks for treating me.
Don't mention it.
You saved me.
Yeah. That was close.
Oh. Right.
It's the first time I saved someone's life.
OK.
By the way, do they sell beer here?
Shall I get you one?
It's so expensive!
A grown-up man scrounging on me...
Tokyo is scary.
It's raining again.
Why did you come to Tokyo?
Er... To visit a relative.
Summer vacation starts early at my school.
Hmm.
If you ever need help, contact me.
See ya, kid.
I won't.
Shower's 280 yen for 20 minutes.
Here.
It suddenly started pouring down again...
Don't you ever learn?
It's a pain to clean up.
Sorry.
Last year's record instances
of sudden torrential rain were
largely exceeded this year...
Great!
Really?
Huh?
Are you really in college?
Where's your ID?
No?
Forget it.
It's not stuff for kids.
Sudden downpours expected...
Tokyo is scary.
I've got to start saving.
Don't sit down here, please.
1,800 yen all you can drink.
Master.
Hey, Mister.
Wait a minute.
Everything the solicitors say is a lie.
Hey, you.
What are you doing here?
Are you a minor?
Hey!
Wait!
You jerk!
Tokyo is scary.
But...
I don't want to go home.
Never again.
Who's this?
Is he sleeping?
On the floor?
Hey,
are you a customer?
No, sorry.
Is he OK?
Leave him alone.
Get out of the way.
Sorry.
It's gotta be a toy.
Er... What's this?
It's for you.
Don't tell anyone.
Huh? But, why?
You've eaten that for
dinner three nights in a row.
I think that was
the most delicious dinner I've
had in all 16 years of my life.
When can we meet again?
How about the day after tomorrow?
Great! I found a nice café.
I'll book a table.
See you, Nagi.
Bye, Ayane.
A grade schooler...
How lucky. I was hoping to see you.
Hi, Kana.
Hello, Nagi.
He's a ladies' man.
Did you curl your hair?
Yes! What do you think?
You look great.
Very lovely.
Tokyo's amazing.
It should be here.
It doesn't work.
Excuse me. I'm Morishima.
I called earlier.
Mr. Suga, are you in?
Mr. Suga?
Wait, this isn't right.
Hello.
Sorry, I'm...
The new assistant.
Kei told me.
Huh? No, I haven't yet...
I'm Natsumi.
Nice to meet you.
Finally, someone else to do the grunt work!
Hey, kid.
Yes?
You looked at my boobs.
I didn't.
What's your name?
Hodaka Morishima.
Hodaka. Beautiful name.
Are you employed here, Natsumi?
Wanna know about me and Kei?
Um, yes.
You're so funny.
It's like you think.
Really?
I've never seen a mistress before.
Long time no see, kid.
Have you lost weight?
Don't tell me you went out gambling again.
You're looking for a job, right?
This is what we're working on now.
We write for time-honored
and prestigious magazines.
Our next feature is "Urban Legends."
Go and interview people who
witnessed or experienced some.
Huh? But, I...
Any topic will do.
Disappearances, human traffic, etc.
You kids like that kinda stuff, right?
How about this?
"The girl who brings sunshine
wherever she goes."
"Sunshine girl"?
I'm like that!
It's raining so much this year.
He ignored me?
There's a demand for that.
Right.
Come on, kid.
You've got zero initiative.
She's got an interview appointment.
Go along and listen.
Me? Now?!
You're on probation!
"Probatory period."
No, really. I can't.
Of course, sunshine girls do exist.
I knew it!
And also rain girls.
The first are possessed by a fox god.
The latter by a dragon god.
Excuse me?
Dragon god individuals drink a lot.
They yearn for water.
They're strong-willed and competitive,
but a bit careless and unreliable.
Maybe that's me.
Fox god individuals are hardworking,
but too weak-hearted to be leaders.
Many are beautiful.
Definitely me.
The weather's off-balance,
so more sunshine and rain girls are born now.
Homeostasis of Gaia theory.
I see.
But, we must be careful.
Messing with nature always has a cost.
Whoever uses too much weather
power gets spirited away.
That's...
I'll be careful.
So, how was it?
A so-called psychic talked at length
about fantasy novel-like stuff.
"If you use too much power
you'll disappear."
I see. That kinda stuff.
Weather isn't some kind of "power."
It's a natural phenomenon.
Look, we're aware of that.
But, we're providing entertainment.
Is that all you've written
so far? You're slow.
Sorry.
But it's not bad.
All right, you're hired.
Wait a minute! I didn't say I was...
It's a live-in job.
Meals included.
Really?
I'll do it! Please hire me.
Good.
What's your name again?
Huh?
Droll.
It's Hodaka.
Right.
It's ready.
Here.
I'm underage, remember?
Let's celebrate Hodaka's hiring.
Cheers!
That was the first meal I shared
with someone since I came to Tokyo.
This is when my new life started.
It was a small editing company,
run by Mr. Suga and Natsumi.
I did all the office chores.
Starting from Mr. Suga's personal care...
Answering the phone, filing receipts,
transcribing interviews.
Is that all you've written so far?
This isn't mine.
Mr. Suga's out of the office...
Sometimes I rode around town with
Natsumi to do some interviews.
They're looking for a sunshine girl.
Hilarious.
My sis' friend's a real sunshine girl.
She calls her the day before a date...
We're not interested.
Then the weather balloon's videosonde
picked up something strange.
A swarm of moving objects
among the cumulonimbi.
Is that all you've written?
You have to buy these when they're on sale.
He's out of the office...
This paragraph's crap.
But this ain't bad.
Mr. Suga, wake up. Come on.
My days were hectic.
But, for the first time
someone was relying on me.
Those rainy days in Tokyo passed in a flash.
Rain.
Rain. Rain. Rain.
There you are.
How's it going, Rain?
Yeah? Good boy.
It's an easy job.
You'll see.
But...
Just give it a try.
You'll get paid right away.
Our club is right there.
That girl...
Give it a go and earn yourself some bucks.
It's right there. Let's go!
But...
Let's go.
Hey! Wait a minute.
Wait!
Just keep running!
Listen to me.
You brat!
Hey, man.
What do you think you're doing?
You were forcing her.
Are you dumb or what?
We've made a deal.
Don't tell me...
You're the brat that was
squatting in front of our club?
What's this, payback?
Please stop it.
Damn!
Get off me!
What's that?
A toy gun?
You really are dumb.
Get up.
You...
What was that for?
To thank me for that burger?
Where did you get that gun?
Who are you?
That's...
I found it.
I thought it was a toy.
It was like a lucky charm for me.
What?
You pointed it at someone.
You could have killed him.
I can't believe it! You make me sick.
You're the worst.
I got fired from my part-time job.
Was it my fault?
No, nothing to do with that burger.
But, that's why I need a well-paid job.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have...
Does it hurt?
Not really.
You're a runaway, aren't you?
I can tell.
But, you can't enjoy Tokyo with this rain.
Huh? Yeah.
Come with me.
It'll clear up now.
Huh?
What do you mean?
A sunshine girl?
I'm Hina.
What's your name?
Hodaka.
How old are you?
16.
Younger than me.
I'll be 18 next month.
You don't look it.
You should treat me with respect.
Pleased to meet you, Hodaka.
Me too.
Mom, there's a fish.
Yeah? Nice.
Don't say bullshit.
I'm serious.
This way.
Look. Over there.
Can't see anything.
It's there.
Look harder.
What's that?
The Kanto region is experiencing
record-breaking rainfall this summer.
It's been raining continuously for two months.
The 30 days forecast predicts more
heavy rain for another month.
The Meteorological Agency said
it's an extremely exceptional...
Too expensive?
Hey!
Look, it's amazing.
They kinda look like fish.
They fell from the sky?
But, they left no trace...
They instantly disappear.
Look.
Remember what the guy
we interviewed said?
The sky's a deeper unknown
world than the sea.
A cumulonimbus can hold
as much water as a whole lake.
So, it could as well harbor
an uncharted ecosystem.
Like these fish?
I guess.
Amazing, isn't it?
If we write about it...
...maybe we can make good money.
Huh? What?
You're starting to sound like Kei.
You'll be a boring grown-up.
Don't put off your sunshine girl.
You're going on a date, right?
It's not a date...
I'm going to look for a job.
What? Don't you work here?
I'm just hanging out.
It's not a date, I said.
I understand how you feel, Keisuke.
But, she finally stopped talking about you.
It'd be cruel to meet her now.
But, I have the right to see her.
Besides, you smoke. Don't you?
Huh?
She's got asthma.
You're too inconsiderate.
I quit smoking a while ago.
But...
You give a bad impression.
It's raining all the time this year.
She can't play outside,
and it's bad for her asthma.
I feel sorry for children nowadays.
We used to have beautiful
springs and summers.
They can't live together
just the two of them.
You're right.
Hold on.
So, possibly...
I'm visiting a girl's home
for the first time!
Welcome, Hodaka.
You got lost, didn't you?
No, er... It's not much, but...
Wow, thank you. Come on in.
Thank you.
Sure.
Did you have lunch?
Not yet. But, it's OK.
Sit there and relax.
Can I use these?
Sure.
Thanks.
Do you live alone?
With my younger brother.
We had some problems.
Problems?
How about you?
Why did you run away?
I found it suffocating to live with my parents.
And in that town.
I see.
Shouldn't you go back?
I don't want to.
Right.
Here you go.
Wow.
I forgot the spring onions!
How do you like living in Tokyo?
Er... Oh.
Come to think of it,
I don't feel like I'm suffocating anymore.
Happy to hear that.
Let's eat.
What? An earthquake?
No, no.
It's the train.
Are you serious, Hodaka?
Well, you're a real sunshine girl, aren't you?
You can clear up the sky just by praying.
Yeah.
Don't you need a job?
I do. But, I can't charge people for that.
I don't think you're cut out for
working in a club like that.
Hodaka.
What are you looking at?
I'm not looking at anything.
Sorry.
Isn't 5,000 yen too expensive?
Shall we do 3,000 yen, then?
Considering living expenses, though...
Maybe we need some graphics.
I'll draw them.
What's this? A hippo?
It's a frog.
Seriously?
It's done!
I'll upload it.
OK?
Yeah.
Hi, I'm home.
I'd like some sardines...
Who are you?
You're the boy on the bus!
Do you know each other?
Hodaka, this is my brother Nagi.
Nagi, this is Hodaka.
He's my business partner.
We've got a request!
You've already uploaded it?
They want good weather for a flea market.
It's tomorrow.
Wait a minute!
Am I really gonna do this?
Widespread rain tomorrow...
It's gonna rain tomorrow.
That's the whole point.
Who the hell is that guy?
It'll be fine.
I'll help you.
How?!
Please use this.
Sorry, I won't.
I've got another secret weapon for you.
Sorry, don't need it.
Cut it out, Hodaka!
Who called those weirdos?
We thought it might bring good luck.
Don't push yourselves too hard.
We're almost there!
Water, Hina?
Do you want a candy?
Tell them to go home.
OK.
The sky's clearing up.
No way!
It cleared up.
It's been ages, huh?
Look! Look!
Finally, after so long.
The sky's so beautiful.
Amazing.
What do you think?
You're awesome, guys.
You're a real sunshine girl.
I'm so surprised.
You're great.
Even if it was a coincidence.
It wasn't.
Here's 20,000 yen.
It's too much.
You get a bonus because you're cute.
Thank you so much.
We'll sell a lot more now.
Yaay!
Amazing!
I feel I can do this.
Cool! Let's make money with the weather.
Yeah!
The human mind works in mysterious ways.
You just need to see the sun shining
in the morning to feel energized.
A blue sky makes you feel happy you're alive.
It makes you feel more in love
with that someone by your side.
It's a once in a lifetime event.
I wanna wear white under a blue sky.
To watch the meteor shower.
It never wins on rainy days!
I've worked hard in that
sweatshop just for today!
I want to play outside.
Everyone had their own reason
to pursue sunshine in rainy Tokyo.
Hina was able to clear only
small spots for a brief time.
But, the sky would always
answer her prayers.
She was really the "100% sunshine girl."
It was like the whole town was dressing up.
What a wonderful world
I was born in, I thought.
Smile, please.
Go! Go! Keep going!
Look, there's more!
Kawaii... kawaii...
Go! Go!
Thanks.
Thank you.
Thanks
Thank you so much.
We're really influenced by the weather.
I realized how much the human
heart is connected with the sky.
I'm off.
To where?
Is it canceled due to rain?
It's past noon.
When does it start?
I've changed my clothes to come here.
Shall we go home?
I'm tired.
I've read online that the
"100% sunshine girl" is amazing.
But, this is such a big event.
Do you really want to rely on that?
It's going to rain all week.
We won't be able to postpone it.
In this situation,
we're even ready to rely on a charm.
The Jingu Gaien fireworks
will start at 7 p.m. as scheduled.
I'm in love.
With this sunshine girl job.
I finally found my role in life.
Maybe.
Or maybe not.
Or maybe not not.
Maybe not not...?
Yes or no?
You're too serious.
Thank you, Hodaka.
Weather is a mystery.
The way the sky looks can move you so much.
Hina really moves my heart.
Yesterday's Jingu Gaien fireworks
were blessed with miraculous sunshine.
But, strong rain is back again
today, just like a backlash.
The temperature in the capital is
now 21°C, much lower than average.
It's unusually chilly for August.
Make sure you wear a light jacket...
You're my first company of choice.
Be careful not to catch a cold.
Record rainfall and low temperatures
are driving food prices up.
Lettuce is three times more expensive than last year.
Oh, that project? Right,
we've put it on hold.
Sorry, we're not going ahead with it.
I see.
Yes. OK.
I'll do my best,
so please call us again.
What?
Hello, this is the Mamiya household.
Hello, it's Keisuke.
Sorry to rush you.
Regarding the visit...
You're late, Kei.
It's an important interview.
Are we in a bad mood?
No luck with work?
Where's Hodaka?
Busy with his other job?
He's neglecting work lately.
Just let him be.
We're not that busy.
He took in that cat.
You did the same with him.
Huh?
You helped him because he
reminded you of yourself.
How much are you paying him?
Only 30,000 yen?
That's so low.
Nope. It's 3,000 yen.
What?
Are you serious? 3,000 yen a month?
That's exploitation.
Look ahead.
You're gonna get sued.
Actually, I'll report you.
He gets free food and accommodation,
and the company pays his phone bills.
Ugh!
No wonder he's got an extra job.
I'm surprised.
It's really cleared up.
You kids are amazing.
It's a shame you're quitting.
She was caught on camera.
We got flooded with requests.
We can't cope.
We'll do a last one then stop for a while.
She looks tired, too.
Got guests, Granny?
Oh, you're here.
I came to help.
Very young guests.
Are you Granny's friends?
Hello.
I've asked for nice weather
on my husband's first anniversary.
It stopped raining, in fact.
It'd be hard for him
to come back if it was raining.
"Come back"?
They say the dead come back
from the sky around August 15.
So, he died a year ago?
Yes.
My mom too.
You lost your mother last year?
Yes.
Light a welcoming fire for her.
She'll protect you.
Thanks.
He'll follow the smoke and come back.
From where?
From heaven.
There's always been
another world, up in the sky.
Apparently, this is what
the Weather Maiden saw.
It's a mysterious painting.
Flying fish in the sky.
And even a dragon.
It's beautiful.
Right?
The "Weather Maiden"
was like a shaman, right?
Huh? What?
Was she like a shaman?
Yeah.
Fixing the weather is the
Weather Maiden's work.
Fixing it?
Sounds like a con.
Like this year's abnormal weather?
There's nothing abnormal about that.
They say "in recorded history,"
but when did records begin?
100 years ago at best.
How old do you think this is?
800 years old.
800?
Don't get too excited, Grandpa.
The weather changes on a whim.
Regardless of human needs.
We can't even tell what's
the norm and what isn't.
We're only allowed to stay temporarily
in the space between the sky and earth,
clinging hard not to be shaken off.
We used to be well aware of this in the past.
But, there's a thin thread
linking us humans and the sky.
The Weather Maiden.
A special girl who can take in people's
wishes and deliver them to the sky.
In ancient times, there was one
in every village and every country.
Kei. It sounds like the sunshine girl.
Are you sure you want to
listen to my grandpa?
It all sounds pretty far-fetched.
It's a very interesting story.
We're thankful.
But, everything comes at a price.
A tragic fate awaits the Weather Maiden.
One, two, three.
Your turn.
Thanks for keeping Granny company.
We're actually here because of work.
Join us, Granny.
They're having fun.
How old are you guys?
I'm 16. She's...
She said it's her birthday next week.
Really? You've gotta buy her a present.
Come eat some watermelon.
Yaay!
Thank you.
Hey, wait!
Dang.
Jeez. Why?
Wait a minute.
I didn't know she was a minor, I swear.
It's not about that?
I told you it wasn't.
You made us run for nothing.
That's you, right?
Can you tell us about this boy?
A high school boy?
Maybe he picked up by chance
the gun Shibata threw away.
In that case, he might have posted about it.
Online, you mean?
Kids write all sorts of stuff
on social networks nowadays.
Go, Nagi!
You're amazing, Nagi!
You're the best.
A ring. Definitely.
Really? Isn't it too serious?
It's for my sister's birthday, right?
I've asked another woman
for reference, but...
What I'd like to get?
Hugs and kisses. Cash.
A decent boyfriend. And a job.
It wasn't helpful at all.
A ring...
Bye bye, Nagi.
See you, Nagi.
You're in love with Hina, aren't you?
What?
Er, it's not like that.
Or maybe it is?
Being ambivalent is
the worst thing for a man.
Really?
Be clear before you start dating and
be ambiguous later. It's the basics.
Can I call you Nagi Sempai?
Hina's been working all
the time since Mom died.
She's been doing it for me,
because I'm still a kid.
So, I want her to do more teenage-like stuff.
I don't know if you're the right guy, though.
Thank you very much.
Er, do you think she'll like it?
Huh?
It took you three hours to choose it.
If it were I, I'd be very happy to receive it.
I wish you the best of luck.
Tomorrow's sunshine girl job will be our last.
A man requested good weather
at the park for his daughter.
After that,
I'll give Hina the ring.
Daddy, do it again.
One more time!
Right. Ready?
Go!
Ow.
This is bad for your back.
Why you, Mr. Suga?
Did you know this was my job?
You knew and said nothing?
Actually, you have a daughter?
I'm stunned.
Today's forecast was 100% rain.
My daughter has asthma.
She lives with her granny,
who won't let me see her on rainy days.
Nothing can beat a gorgeous blue sky.
So, you're Hodaka's boss.
I also saved his life.
Why does she treat you like a little boy?
Hina's two years older than me.
Huh? 16, 17, 18. Same stuff.
I guess.
It's not.
There you are!
Hi, guys!
Aren't you gonna be in trouble?
Does Natsumi know you're married?
What's up with you guys?
Hodaka thought you were my...
Mistress?
You didn't tell me you were uncle and niece.
That's a disgusting fantasy.
You're dirty-minded.
Hey, Hodaka.
You looked at my boobs.
I didn't!
Natsumi!
Hello, Moka!
Daddy, I made a garland. It's for you.
Really?
Come here, Hodaka.
My sempai's calling me.
Hodaka's hilarious.
He's such a kid.
Don't you think they're similar?
Hodaka and Mr. Suga?
Yep.
Kei ran away from home and came
to Tokyo when he was a teen.
He met his future wife
and fell in love big time.
But, she died in an accident some years ago.
He's still in love with her.
I've been dying to meet you for so long, Hina.
The 100% sunshine girl.
You're amazing.
I wish I had a skill like that
on my resume. I hate looking for a job.
I wish I was still in high school too.
I can't wait to be a grown-up instead.
Right.
Good to see you're OK.
I was actually a bit worried.
Are you tired, Moka?
Here, take a breath.
One, two, three.
I'm fine. Let's play!
I don't think...
I guess we'll leave now.
I want to spend more time with Nagi!
Why don't we all go to dinner together?
But...
I'll go eat with Moka. Is it OK?
Sure.
Yaay!
Hodaka, take Hina home.
Hey.
Thank you for bringing the sunshine today!
Thank you.
I'm glad I made you happy.
Oh my god.
Oh my god, Oh my god, Oh my god.
So, possibly this is gonna be...
...the first time I tell a girl I love her.
Hina.
Hodaka.
Sorry.
It's OK.
What is it?
Nothing in particular.
What were you saying?
Hodaka, you know...
I...
Hina!
Hodaka!
Hina?
I think I became a sunshine girl...
...last year, on that day.
I prayed for good weather
all day long the day before.
I wanted to have one last walk
under the sun with my mom.
It looked like a pool of light.
Praying with all my heart,
I crossed the shrine gate.
When I came around,
I was lying on the roof floor.
And the sky was clear.
I think
that's when I got connected to the sky.
Connected to the sky?
Stay in there, Hodaka.
Police. Sorry for the late visit.
The police?
Are you sure you've never seen him?
He's been seen many times around here.
I don't know him.
What has he done?
We want to ask him some questions.
He's a runaway.
His parents filed a missing person's report.
Also, you're living alone
with your little brother, right?
That's right.
That's a bit of a problem too.
Without a guardian, you...
But!
We don't bother anyone.
Hina.
She'll come back tomorrow
with the social service.
What can I do?
They'll separate us!
Hodaka! The police were...
I know. Go home,
I'll come later.
Temperatures have fallen sharply after sunset.
Mr. Suga?
Surprised by my new look?
I'm in disguise.
The police came to my office.
They're treating it like a kidnapping.
I denied any involvement,
but they suspect me.
Take it.
It's your severance pay.
Don't come back to the office.
They'll arrest me.
I filed for custody of my daughter.
It's a delicate time, sorry.
Go back home tomorrow.
Then everything will go back to normal.
It'll be best for everyone.
It's time to grow up, kid.
We can't stay here anymore.
But, where are you...
I don't know, but...
Anywhere will do.
As long as I'm with you.
Hodaka, you'd better go
home before you get caught.
You've got a place to go back to.
Don't say that.
We'll be fine.
I'm not going back.
Let's run away together.
A heavy rain special warning has
just been issued in the Tokyo area.
It could be the heaviest rainfall in decades.
Watch out for floods in lowland areas...
A sudden typhoon-strength
low-pressure system...
River flooding. Increasing danger.
Hey, it's overflowing!
Keep calm and walk slowly towards the exit.
Namboku Line Akabane-Iwabuchi
Station, Shibuya Metro Station...
Several flights canceled at Haneda Airport.
Over 6 inches of rain in an hour.
Heavy flooding in many areas of Tokyo.
Are you OK?
Kita Ward, Arakawa Ward, Taito Ward,
Sumida Ward, Shibuya Ward.
You may get stranded.
It's really cold, isn't it?
It's unusually cold for August.
The temperature in Tokyo has fallen below 10°C.
Cumulonimbi keep gathering above Tokyo...
In just an hour, it's like a different season.
I repeat,
A heavy rain special warning has
been issued in the Tokyo area.
The low-pressure system over the Kanto region...
Because of a stream of cold air
over Kanto, very unstable weather...
More heavy rain in central Japan even after dawn...
This abnormal weather will continue for a few weeks.
This abnormal weather is unprecedented
and extremely dangerous.
Due to transportation delays,
Yamanote Line trains are suspended.
What the heck?
Let's get off.
I'll ask Mom to pick us up.
It's freezing.
What should we do?
Let's look for a place to sleep tonight.
I'm sorry, we're fully booked.
Do you have a reservation?
We're full.
Only the three of you?
Do you have ID?
We can't accept unaccompanied minors.
It's not a matter of money.
It's no place for kids.
You guys...
Are you runaways?
Hina, Hodaka. Look!
Snow?
Hina is connected with the sky...?
It's freezing!
Hey Kei, it's snowing in August.
The world's finally gone crazy.
Oh?
It's unbelievable, but it's snowing here in Tokyo.
Kei, wake up.
You'll catch a cold.
Asuka.
Asuka. You too, Kei. Smile.
Brr.
You look like an old man, Kei.
You know, once you grow old
you can't switch your priorities anymore.
What are you saying?
Where's Hodaka?
You kicked him out?
I can't believe it!
I told you, the police showed up.
I've got to protect myself.
So, you smoked a pack of cigarettes
and got drunk because you felt guilty.
That's so uncool, meow.
Even Rain's saying it.
Really uncool.
So last century.
Can you stay away?
You smell old.
You're uncool too.
What's her name... Hina?
If the story about
the Weather Maiden being...
...a human sacrifice is true,
then one day she'll...
But, that's...
What should I have done, then?
Don't get so uptight.
It's just bullshit.
But, if it was true...
If you could fix this crazy weather
with one human sacrifice,
I'd be happy.
Everyone would.
A heavy rain and heavy snow
warning has been issued.
Don't go out if it's not strictly necessary...
Please follow local government
evacuation instructions.
You kids.
It's dangerous to walk around unsupervised.
Are you all siblings?
Er...
We're going home.
I'm a college student.
They're my younger brothers.
I see.
Can you show me your ID?
I don't have it on me.
Maybe it's him.
He may be carrying a gun. Be careful.
And you? Are you in high school?
That's a big backpack.
Can you remove your hood?
Hina.
Run away.
Hey! Wait!
Stop!
Gotcha!
Let me go!
Resisting arrest.
Stop struggling.
Hodaka!
Stop!
Hina.
Please!
It's dangerous.
Let's go, Hina.
Jeez.
Let's go take a look.
Sempai.
It's 28,000 yen a night.
28,000 yen. Can you pay?
Huh? Yes. I'll pay.
Seems like I'm a wanted man now.
That's so cool.
I was really worried.
You almost got arrested.
I totally panicked.
There's nothing to laugh about.
This room is huge!
The bed's huge!
The bathroom's huge!
Hina. Hodaka.
Let's take a bath together.
Do it alone.
Hodaka, let's take a
boys-only bath together.
It's so warm.
What's this?
Wow!
Amazing.
Switch.
There's a lot of stuff.
What do you want?
Let's try them all, Sempai.
Are you sure?
I got severance pay.
Hina, we're having a
gorgeous dinner tonight.
Looking forward to it.
Here I am.
Welcome back.
Let's eat.
Let me try that, Hodaka.
The curry's yummy.
Yakisoba's delicious.
I want some too.
Isn't it too early, Hodaka?
Tastes yummier if you
wait only two minutes.
Dear God, if you really exist, I beg you.
This is more than enough.
We don't need anything else.
We'll manage somehow.
So please, don't give us anything more,
and don't take anything more from us.
I beg you please, Dear God.
Let us be together like this forever.
Hina.
Happy 18th birthday.
It's cheap, but I've picked
something that'd look good on you.
Thanks.
Tell me, Hodaka.
Would you like this rain to stop?
Yes.
I was chosen to be a human sacrifice.
Natsumi told me about
the sunshine girl's fate.
She gets sacrificed and disappears,
then the weather goes back to normal.
Come on.
They're always telling weird stories.
It's not like people disappear...
What are you looking at?
I'm not looking...
I'm looking at you.
Why are you crying?
The more I pray for sunshine,
the more my body becomes transparent.
I'm sure that, if I die this way,
the usual summer will come back.
Take care of Nagi.
No.
No way. You're not going anywhere.
We'll live together.
The three of us.
Hodaka.
Let's make a promise, Hina.
We'll always be together.
I'll work. I'll earn enough for all of us.
You quit the sunshine girl job.
Your body will go back to normal.
So...
I had a dream.
I was still on the island.
I wanted to leave.
I was rushing desperately,
trying to reach the light.
When I thought I did,
I reached a dead end instead.
Then I decided I wanted to enter that light.
And at the edge of it,
I found you.
I had a dream.
The day I met you.
You looked like a lost kitten.
But you've found a meaning for my existence.
I kept working as the sunshine girl
'cos I was happy to make people smile.
I'm really glad I've met you.
So, don't cry, Hodaka.
What is this place?
Hodaka...
Hina?
Where are you?
Hina.
Hina?
What's wrong, Hodaka?
Hina's disappeared.
I just dreamt...
that she was disappearing in the sky.
Don't tell me...
Open the door.
Open up!
What?
Hodaka Morishima, right?
You're a missing person.
And suspected of unlawful
possession of a weapon.
Come to the police station.
Let me go!
I won't hurt you.
Let me go, I said!
Hodaka!
Sempai.
Don't struggle.
Keep going.
After months of rain, the Kanto plain is
finally seeing some brilliant sunshine.
It seems unreal.
In the last few hours, a sudden change in...
By 8am. the temperature was already over 25°C.
Many areas around the Arakawa river are flooded.
The transport system is still paralyzed...
The extent of the damage has yet to be assessed.
It'll take a few days at least for recovery.
Everyone looks happy under the clear blue sky.
Hey, look at the sky.
Is it for real?
It's sunny.
It cleared up!
The sky's so clear.
I feel like crying.
Finally, real summer has arrived.
What are you doing?
Hina...
...sacrificed herself.
Hina! Tell me it's not true!
Hey!
Hina!
I've got a question.
The girl who was with you yesterday
is 15-year-old Hina Amano, right?
Do you know where she is?
Hina's 15?
Not 18?
She faked her resume at work.
I guess she had to make a living,
but she's still in middle school.
Compulsory school age.
Didn't you know?
What the heck?
I'm the oldest one.
What a pain.
Don't you know where she may be?
The sky has cleared because
she offered herself in exchange.
And nobody knows that...
I can't take it.
This is a pain.
Will we need an expert medical witness?
It's clear.
Daddy! Did you look outside?
Yeah, I did.
I dreamt of Hina.
I'm sure it was her who
brought the sunshine again.
Yeah.
Maybe you're right.
Excuse me.
Detective, I've got a favor to ask you.
What?
Let me go look for Hina.
It's my turn to help her now.
I'll come back as soon as I find her.
I'll listen to you in here. Come on.
Tell Mr. Yasui we'll interrogate him now.
Yes, Sir.
Hey! Wait!
Wait!
Someone stop him!
Stop!
That brat!
Don't let him get out of here.
Stop!
Bastard.
What the hell?!
Cheeky bastard.
Cross the street.
Yes Sir!
Darn!
Hodaka.
Natsumi?
What are you doing?
I'm going to find Hina.
Get on.
That brat!
Nagi called.
He said Hina has disappeared
and you got arrested.
Where is he?
At the Child Consultation Center.
How exciting.
We're outlaws now!
Where are we going, then?
What? Another visitor?
Oh, another girl.
He's popular.
Nagi.
Ayane! You're here too.
Kana, this is Ayane.
Pleased to meet you.
Ayane, this is Kana.
Nice to meet you.
And she's officer Sasaki.
She'll be here with me all day.
You're like a VIP, Nagi.
Pleased to meet you.
Thank you so much for coming.
Sorry for the sudden news.
Really! When I heard they took you
into custody, my heart almost stopped.
Same for me.
My heart's still pounding.
Touch and feel it, Nagi.
Oh, you're right.
Excuse me.
Yes?
It's my first visit.
I'm a bit nervous.
Huh?
I need the toilet.
Oh, OK.
Thanks, I owe you one.
Jeez. You even call your ex
when you need something.
Here.
Look the other way.
I'll take my clothes off.
Mr. Keisuke Suga.
Thanks for yesterday.
You again?
Summer's finally back
the way it should, huh?
I told you I know nothing
about that runaway boy.
Can we check out your office for a minute?
Hey, what's that for?
Oh, it's flooded.
There's no one in there.
Well, it's a bit embarrassing, but...
Huh? He ran away?
From the police station?
A derelict building in Yoyogi?
That's where she became a sunshine girl.
Bend down!
She said she got connected to the sky
on the roof of that building.
So, if I go there, I'm sure...
Oh, no!
You, on that bike! Stop!
Hold tight!
Whoa!
Natsumi!
Am I awesome or what?
I think I was born for this.
Maybe...
...I should become a speed cop!
They won't hire you now.
As for the reason for his escape...
I think he may be searching
for the girl who was with him.
It's a strange story.
He said she's disappeared in
exchange for this good weather.
What? Don't tell me you...
No, I don't believe it.
But, he's throwing his life away.
And all because there's a girl
he wants to meet so badly.
Makes me feel a bit envious.
There's not much point in telling me that.
Mr. Suga, you...
Huh?
Are you OK?
Why?
Well, you are...
...crying.
Oh, no.
We're jumping in!
Can't go any further.
Go, Hodaka.
Thank you, Natsumi.
Hodaka!
Run!
Hina.
Hina, Hina, Hina!
Are you there? Hina!
Hey, Hodaka.
It'll clear up now.
It's for you.
You've eaten that for dinner
three nights in a row.
Does it hurt?
You're a runaway, aren't you?
But, you can't enjoy Tokyo with this rain.
Younger than me.
I'll be 18 next month.
You should treat me with respect.
Are you hungry, Hodaka?
Sit there and relax.
How do you like living in Tokyo?
Come to think of it,
I don't feel like I'm suffocating anymore.
Happy to hear that.
I'm in love with this sunshine girl job.
Thank you, Hodaka.
Someone got onto the tracks.
Who's that?
Hey, you!
It's dangerous!
Hey! What are you doing?
It's dangerous! Stop!
What's that? Hilarious.
What is he doing?
There's someone running.
He'll get arrested.
There are idiots like that.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Hina!
I made you do that sunshine girl thing.
You've shouldered all responsibility.
Tell me...
...Hodaka.
Would you like this rain to stop?
Mr. Suga?
I was looking for you, Hodaka.
Why?
Do you realize what you're doing?
Hina's disappeared.
It's my fault. The sunshine
girl job was my idea.
Hodaka, you...
It's my turn to help her now!
I must go.
Wait!
Where are you...
I can go to heaven through there!
What are you saying?
She's in the sky!
I'll use the emergency stairs.
She can't be up there...
I have to help her!
Get a grip!
Calm down.
Go back to the police station.
They'll understand.
You've done nothing wrong.
If you keep running away, it'll be too late.
You know that.
Suspect's car found.
Going to apprehend him.
Don't worry,
I'll come with you.
Let's explain everything together, OK?
Let me go! Please!
Calm down.
Get off me!
You bastard!
Don't stand in my way!
Hodaka. That's...
Let me go see Hina.
Hodaka Morishima.
Drop the gun.
Hey, wait a minute.
It's a misunderstanding.
I'll explain.
Right, Hodaka?
You...
Put the gun down, Morishima.
Please don't make me shoot.
Hodaka.
Come on Hodaka,
just put it down.
What's wrong with you guys?
He's just a kid!
Leave me alone!
Why are you holding me up?
You all know nothing.
You pretend you don't.
I just want to see her...
...once more!
Got him!
Let go of me!
Take your hands off Hodaka, assholes!
You bastard!
Go, Hodaka!
Stop!
Hodaka.
Nagi!
Hey!
It's all your fault, Hodaka.
Bring my sister back!
Dear God,
please, please, please.
Please!
Sky fish?
Hina!
Hodaka!
Jump!
I found you!
Hodaka! Hodaka!
Don't let go of my hands.
OK.
Hina!
Hodaka!
Let's go home, Hina.
But, if I do, the weather will...
It's OK.
It's enough.
You don't have to be
the sunshine girl anymore.
Who cares if we don't
see the sunshine again.
I want you more than any blue sky.
The weather...
...can stay crazy!
Pray for yourself...
...Hina.
OK.
Hodaka.
The rain started falling again
that day, and never stopped.
It's slowly sinking Tokyo into the water.
And it's still falling now,
three years later.
How fast time flies, I can't believe
how quickly the moments have passed...
The precious years have come
and gone too soon, here with you
I've learned from you the right
way to do what must be done
What can I say?
Morishima Sempai!
Er... You're moving to Tokyo, aren't you?
Huh? Yeah.
Come on, ask him.
It's now or never.
So, possibly, this is...
You know...
There's something
I've always wanted to ask you.
...the first time someone
tells me they love me?
I'd like to know...
Er...
Is it true you're wanted
by the police in Tokyo?
Huh?
That summer of three years ago,
I was arrested and went on trial.
They put me on probation until graduation.
The island, my parents'
house and the school...
They all were the same old places
where I was supposed to live.
But, I just kept quietly
waiting for graduation.
I haven't...
...seen Hina since that day.
I have no idea what I'll think
seeing Tokyo after it changed,
nor what I'll say to her.
Tomorrow's weather for the Kanto region.
It will rain again all day.
Now I need to find a part-time job.
The high will be 15°C. Same or slightly
hotter than today in most areas.
Oh, right...
Speaking of part-time jobs...
It's still there.
It was a sunshine girl request
from two years ago.
Next stop Takashimadaira.
Look who's here.
Are you alone?
Where's the sunshine girl?
She's no longer a sunshine girl.
I came just to tell you that.
Don't trouble yourself.
You moved.
You used to live in an older house downtown.
The whole area is under water now.
I'm sorry.
Why do you apologize?
Um...
You know, that area
used to be under the sea.
Until 200 years ago.
In old times, Tokyo was just a bay.
Human beings and the weather
changed it, little by little.
So, well... I think it's just
gone back to its original self.
What the heck...?
You've been thinking about
that crap for three years?
Don't say that...
You're about to start college,
but you're still acting like a kid.
But, that day we...
You two caused this?
You changed the world?
Bullshit.
Don't flatter yourself, dummy.
Look, I went on a date with my daughter.
But, Natsumi and Nagi were in the way.
Stop brooding over stupid
stuff and go see her.
Why haven't you?
I was on probation.
I didn't want to cause her trouble.
She doesn't even have a cellphone.
And I'm so nervous.
I don't know what to say to her.
Rain? You're so big now.
Come on, get out of here.
Go now. I've got work to do!
Just go to her house.
Thank you for your time.
Come back again.
Hey.
Don't sweat it, young man.
The world's always been crazy anyway.
Next stop Hamamatsucho.
You're super positive.
You think?
Looking forward to the picnic.
Yeah!
It was under the sea.
The world's always been crazy.
So, it's no one's fault that it's like this.
Is this what I should say to her?
No. That's not it.
That day, I...
We changed the world.
I made a choice.
I've chosen her. I've chosen this world.
I've chosen to live here.
Hina!
Hodaka!
What's wrong?
Are you OK?
Yeah.
Hina, I'm sure...
...we're gonna be OK.